Guide to the Howe family papers, 1854-1935
Howe family papers, 1854-1935
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Howe Family Papers, 1854-1855, 1905-1935
6373
Howe family, 1854-1855, 1905-1935
.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence from Almon A. Jaynes to Grace Howe. WWI letters to Grace Howe from a number of soldiers. Twenty-six daily diaries of Grace Howe, 1905-1935. Photographs of Grace Howe, her sister Josephine Howe, A. A. Jaynes, among others.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Henry J. Howe enlisted on Aug. 24, 1861 at Vesper, N.Y., mustered in as a private, Oneida Independent company, Cavalry in September of 1861. He served three years and mustered out in September of 1864.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence from Almon A. Jaynes, Chaplain 3rd New York Infantry, to Grace Howe of Syracuse, N.Y. Other WWI letters to Grace Howe from a number of soldiers. Twenty-six daily diaries of Grace Howe, 1905-1935. Photographs of Grace Howe, her sister Josephine Howe, A. A. Jaynes, among others. Transcript of Howe family diaries; also letters of a Steuben County family.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Howe, Henry J.; Howe, Henry J.; Howe, Josephine.; Jaynes, Almon A.; King, Dorris Howe.
Subjects:
United States. Army.; United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 3rd (1914-1918); Oneida Independent Company, Cavalry.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; World War, 1914-1918--Personal narratives
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Henry J. Howe Civil War Materials
Box 1
Series II. Letters
Box 2
Series III. Notes
Box 2
Series IV. Photographs
Box 2
Series V. Diaries
Box 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Henry J. Howe Civil War Materials
  - Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Civil War Letter, 1861-1865 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Transcriptions, 1861-1865 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II. Letters
  - Ellen Cramp, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - James Culver, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Irving J. Davis, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Paul B. Eddy, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lester M. Gilliam, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Almon A. Jaynes, 1907-1916 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Almon A. Jaynes, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Almon A. Jaynes, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Almon A. Jaynes, 1919-1924 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Almon A. Jaynes, 1932-1932 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Almon A. Jaynes (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Thomas S. Knott, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - William Russell, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - J. Kennedy Sebold, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Anna N. Stuart, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Thomas Talbott (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gerald G. True, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series III. Notes
  - Notes, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series V. Diaries
  - G.M. Howe, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1908 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1909 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1910 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1911 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1912 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1913 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1914 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1915 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1916 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1917 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1918 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1919 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1920 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1921 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1922 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1923 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1924 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1925 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1928 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Grace M. Howe, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1931 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1932 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Grace M. Howe, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - [G.M. Howe], 1934 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Grace M. Howe, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Unidentified, journal of building a house (Box 2, Folder 46)